Ruoran Liu Front-end Developer

Ruoran Liu is a front-end developer at ThoughtWorks, Inc. He has been working in ThoughtWorks for 4 years since his graduation. He has been working mostly as a front-end developer and also keen to back-end technologies. He is also passionately engaged with business analysis and project inception.

Skills

Programming Languages: Java, Ruby, Shell, JavaScript **Frameworks**: Drupal, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, ReactJs, Reflux

Testing Tools: JUnit, Rspec, Mockito, Selenium, PhantomJs, Mocha

Web Tools: Less/Sass/Stylus, Browserify, Grunt/Gulp, Bower, jQuery, Underscore/Lodash

DevOps: Jenkins, Vagrant, Chef **Version Control System:** Git, SVN

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sqlite3

Project Experience

2015/09~2015/12:

Leading Global Development Organisation Health Data Visualisation Website

Ruoran was the Technical Leader of the team. The project was for building a visualisation website for health data which was used by managers in both headquarter and underdeveloped countries. Ruoran was fully responsible for making technical decisions and frontend architecture. The project was using React and Reflux as its front-end framework and a Django backend system to provide Restful API. Ruoran also introduced Gulp/Browserify as front-end build tools, and integrated the project to Travis CI.

In the team Ruoran also coached two new joined team members to quickly understand the technical stack used in the project and helped them grow up.

2012/08~2015/08:

Leading Australian Insurance Corporation Portal and Digital Media Website

Ruoran joined the team as a QA and Front-end developer. The project is responsible for 20 websites of the company's brands. Ruoran provided skills of testing automation including continuous integration to the project, collaborating with his colleagues to resolve the challenge of technical stack of Drupal, which the project had been using for a long term. He introduced Selenium and Mocha for website functional tests which are integrated into Jenkins.

Ruoran also participated into development work of the re-design of the banking website. He collaborated with UX designers closely to continuously improve and implement the site using Responsive Design. He integrated perceptual tests to help identify tiny changes of styles in order to achieve a more stable and robust website. The team introduced modern front-end tools such as Sass, Gulp and Browserify to improve the traditional CMS structure.

2012/04~2012/06:

Leading Australian Insurance Corporation Customer Data Integration System

Ruoran was a Developer in the customer data integration project. The project is to simplify the data managing system of the company. The project was developed using Spring Batch with Gradle as the building tool. JBehave is also used as the Behaviour Driven Development tool.

2012/01~2012/04:

Leading Global Development Organisation Infrastructure Tracking Mobile App

Ruoran worked in the project to develop a mobile app in order to track living infrastructure conditions in Uganda for the organisation. The project used Phonegap to build a web app using Javascript and CSS. The project targeted on Blackberry at the beginning and later Android. Ruoran joined as a graduate and quickly became a skilled developer in the team.

Education

MSc in Advanced Computer Science, University of Sheffield, UK, 2010-2011

BEng in Electronic-magnetic Field and Wireless Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, China, 2005 – 2009